안전벨트를 하라는
기장님의 신호입니다.
The captain has turned on
the fasten seatbelt sign.
안전벨트를 확인해 주세요
Please make sure your
seatbelts are securely fastened.
전 독일말 몰라요
덴버 출신이에요. 덴버요
I don't speak german. I'm
from denver. I'm from denver.
- 그냥 폭풍우예요
- 알아요
My friend,it's just an electrical storm.
I understand.
- 껌 드려요?
- 아뇨, 고마워요
Here. Gum?
No,uh,thank you.
자동 항법 스위치
AUTO PILOT ENGAGE
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
SF 인텔리전스
SF
인텔리전스
인
SF 　 텔리전스
텔
SF 인　리전스
리
SF 인텔　전스
전
SF 인텔리　스
스
SF 인텔리전
SF 인텔리전스
SF
인텔리전스
인
SF 　 텔리전스
텔
SF 인　리전스
리
SF 인텔　전스
전
SF 인텔리　스
스
SF 인텔리전
SF 인텔리전스
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
ht
tp: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
tp
ht　: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
:
http　//club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
//
http: 　club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
cl
http: //　ub.ipop.co.kr/foundation
ub
http: //cl　.ipop.co.kr/foundation
.i
http: //club　pop.co.kr/foundation
po
http: //club.i　p.co.kr/foundation
p.
http: //club.ipo　co.kr/foundation
co
http: //club.ipop.　.kr/foundation
.k
http: //club.ipop.co　r/foundation
r/
http: //club.ipop.co.k　foundation
fo
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/　undation
un
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/fo　dation
da
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foun　tion
ti
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/founda　on
on
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundati
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
ht
tp: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
tp
ht　: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
:
http　//club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
//
http: 　club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
cl
http: //　ub.ipop.co.kr/foundation
ub
http: //cl　.ipop.co.kr/foundation
.i
http: //club　pop.co.kr/foundation
po
http: //club.i　p.co.kr/foundation
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
sync:峠흄흄
p.
http: //club.ipo　co.kr/foundation
co
http: //club.ipop.　.kr/foundation
.k
http: //club.ipop.co　r/foundation
r/
http: //club.ipop.co.k　foundation
fo
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/　undation
un
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/fo　dation
da
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foun　tion
ti
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/founda　on
on
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundati
http: //club.ipop.co.kr/foundation
한글
한글자
한글자막
패
불
기
뚜
한글자막:
패
불
기
뚜
한글자막:
패
불
기
한글자막:　뚜
패
불
한글자막:　뚜기
패
한글자막:　뚜기불
한글자막:　뚜기불패
한글자막: 뚜기불패
Fringe
Season01 Episode01
한글자막: 뚜기불패
영어 자막
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
sync:峠흄흄
- 맙소사
- 왜?
- Oh,my god.
- what?
- 침대 소리가 너무 커
- 그래?
- This bed is loud.
- You think?
계속 이럴 수는 없어
We--we can't
keep doing this.
- 몰래 만나는 거 말이야
- 부서에서 사내 로맨스는 시끄럽잖아
Sneaking around.
Department's not a massive
fan of office romance.
규칙 세미나는 끝도 없이 길지 않았어?
The policy seminar
was endless,wasn't it?
난 계속 당신을 보고 있더라고
멈추려고 의자를 움직여야만 했지
I kept finding myself staring at you.
Actually had to move my chair to stop.
- 찰리가 아는 것 같아
- 아니, 모를 거야
- Well,I--I think charlie
knows. - No,he doesn't know.
- 아는 것 같아
- 알았다면 다른 곳으로 보냈을 거야
Well,I think he does.
If he knew,you would be transferred.
누가 명령을 내리던 말던
당신과 난 같은 도시에 살아야만 해
The idea of somebody making a call whether
or not you and I get to live in the same city,
받아들일 수 없어
that's unacceptable to me.
여하튼 어떤 위험이 있어도
난...
Anyway,that's all just preamble
to the kicker,which is that...
당신을 사랑해
I love you.
올리비아 던함입니다
Olivia dunham.
네
Yes,sir.
물론입니다
Of course,sir.
네, 바로 가죠
Yes,sir,I'm on my way.
로건 국제공항에 사건이야
찰리도 오고 있데
Incident at logan. International
flight. Charlie's on his way.
스캇 요원입니다
Agent scott.
보스턴 로건 공항
LOGAN AIRPORT BOSTON
FBI에게 권한을 드리죠
We're gonna let the fbi take the lead.
FBI 올리비아 던함입니다
Olivia dunham,fbi.
함부르크에서 출발한 비행기야
승객은 147명이고
we got a flight out of
hamburg. 147 passengers.
관제탑과 소식이 끊긴 지는 3시간 됐어
Towers lost contact three hours in.
전자기 방해가 있었다고 생각했었나 봐
They thought it might have
been electrical interference.
우리 영해로 들어와서도 무전이 안 되자
They entered our airspace radio silent.
해군에서 2대의 F-18기를 보냈어
Navy then scrambles
two f-18s for escort.
창문은 더럽고
They reported stains on the windows.
산 사람이 없다고 보고를 했어
No signs of life aboard the jet.
백악관에서 CDC가 도착하기 전에
비행기 문을 열지 못하게 했대
(CDC= 질병 대책 센터)
White house approved a cdc request for
the jet not to be opened until they arrive.
산 사람이 없다고?
그럼 비행기 운전은 누가 했는데?
No signs of life? Who
was flying the plane?
로건 공항은 자동 항법 시스템을 갖춘
최초의 공항이야
Logan's one of the first airports
with the pearl autopilot system.
비행기는 제시간에 착륙을 했다네
내가 그동안 타 왔던 비행기와는 다르게
Plane landed itself right on time.
Unlike every flight I've ever taken.
확실히 해주지
우린 널 기꺼이 가족처럼 대해줄 수 있어
well,let me assure you we'd be
happy to treat you asamily too.
NTSB는 자기네가 경찰인지 알아
(NTSB= 미국연방 교통안전 위원회)
Good old ntsb. They all
like to think they're cops.
- 스캇 요원
- 패랜시스 요원, 던함 요원
- Agent scott.
- Agent francis. Agent dunham.
맥니어리가 창문에서 뭘 봤는지는 몰라도
Whatever the hell mcneary
saw through that window,
대원들 앞에서 토를 했다더군
it made him throw up in
front of his whole unit.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
무슨 일이에요?
사고라도 났나요?
So what's going on here?
Some sort of accident?
공항 도로는 폐쇄됐습니다
Tarmac's closed.
걱정하지 않으셔도 돼요
Nothing you need to worry about,sir.
그렇군요
Oh,all right.
- 차를 빼세요
- 그러죠
- Move along.
- I'll do that.
고마워요
Thanks.
여러 부서에서 나왔지만
Although this is a joint task force,
모두 국토 안보국에 보고해야 한다
you're all reporting to the
department of homeland security.
난 책임을 맡은
특수요원 브로일스다
I'm special agent in charge broyles.
D.C.에서 날 이곳에 보낸 이유는
해답을 원해서야
D.C.Has sent me here to
make sure we get results.
안으로 들어가기 위해서는
4단계 방역복을 착용해야 한다
Standard level four hazmat
suits are required to go in.
각 부서의 다음 사람들은 준비해
Members from each agency on
the starting line as follows.
CIA의 베로노프
Cia,baronoff.
FBI의 찰리 프랜시스와 존 스캇
Fbi,charlie francis and john scott.
나머지는 대기하도록
Everyone else stand by.
좋아. 모두 가지
Okay,people,let's move.
요원님!
Sir!
FBI 연락 부서 올리비아 던함입니다
Olivia dunham,fbi interagency liaison.
특별 조사 연락 부서라
사랑받는 부서지
Liaison on an interagency
task force. Gotta love that.
반짝이는 도넛 위에 뿌려진
설탕처럼 말이야
Kind of like powdered
sugar on a glazed donut.
죄송하지만, 제 일을 효과적으로 하려면
정보를 즉각 받아야만 해요
Excuse me,if I'm gonna do my job
effectively,I like my information first-hand.
여분의 인력이 아니고
책임감이죠
That's not redundancy.
That's accountability.
당신이 누구인지 정확히 알아
I know exactly who you are.
들어가고 싶나? 연락 부서양?
옷을 입어
You want in,liaison?
Suit up.
어떤 테러리스트가 이런 짓을 했지?
What kind of terrorism is this?
테러리스트인지 어찌 알아?
Who says it's terrorism?
정보원에 의하면
승객을 꺼내지 않은 채로
sources tell us the plane was
deliberately set ablaze by the cdc
CDC에서 비행기를
고의로 태웠다고 합니다
after all passengers'
remains had been removed...
보스턴 연방 빌딩
FEDERAL BUILDING BOSTON
좌석 41A, 존 로젠블룸
하와이 호놀룰루, 자동차 판매원
seat 41a,john rosenbloom.
Honolulu,hawaii. Car salesman.
범죄 경력 없음
Criminal history's negative.
함부르크 공항의 비디오를 다시 봤나요?
Have we reviewed video
from the hamburg airport?
승객 중에 아픈 사람이
있었는지 확인해야겠어요
We need to see if any passengers...
오는 중이에요
On its way.
근데 블랙박스는 왜 이리 늦게 오는 거지?
And what the hell is taking
so long with that black box?
공항은 폐쇄했겠죠?
Please tell me that terminal's shutdown.
현지 시각 0400시 이후로 폐쇄 됐어
질문이 더 있나?
It's been down since 0400 local.
You got any more questions?
펠리 요원에게 뼈 조직을 넘긴 사람은
CDC의 누구죠?/집 전화번호라도 줄까?
Who's point from cdc
on the bone tissue...
agent paley. You want his home number?
아니요. 하지만, 보고서 전체가 필요해요
No,but I'd like the whole report.
- 이런 팩스가 아니고요
- 연락 부서가 너무 많아
- And not just this fax--
- we're on that too liaison.
기내 영화 때문에 이런 일이
벌어진 것 같지는 않군
We don't think what happened on that
plane was a result of the in-flight movie.
저장 시설의 경비가 0300시에
백 베이 경찰에게 전화했대요
Back bay pd got a call at 0300 from
a guard on duty at a storage facility.
2명을 봤는데, 의심스러운 중동 사람이
백인에게 가방을 줬다네요
He saw two,and I quote,"suspicious middle
eastern men" handing a white guy a briefcase.
연락 부서양, 가서 알아봐
Liaison,take it. Go find out.
뭘요? 저거요?
Take what? That?
나보고 저런 걸 알아보라고요?
You're telling me that's my assignment?
맞아
해주실래요?
Yeah,honey. Would you mind?
질병 대책 센터에 의하면
in conjunction with the
center for disease control,
비행기를 태운 이유는...
the decision was made to burn the
plane only after it was determined--
매사추세츠 첼시 U-CASE 장고 보관소
U-CASE STORAGE CHELSEA,MASSACHUSETTS
비열한 놈, 그놈 친구가 3명의
해병대원에게 성추행해서
petty bastard.
He's pissed because his best friend
sexually assaulted three marine privates,
내가 처벌을 했는데 그 점이 화난 거야
and I'm the bad guy
'cause I put him away.
브로일스는 멍청이야
Broyles is an idiot.
네가 더 똑똑하고 더 강하고
훨씬 예뻐서
You're smarter,you're
stronger,you're much better looking.
질투하는 거라고
He's jealous.
왜?
What?
모텔에서 내게 사랑한다고 했어
You said you loved me.
In the motel.
맞아
Yeah.
의미 있는 일이었어
That was a big deal.
돌아오는 말이 없기에
그냥 잊었어
Yeah,well,you didn't say
anything back,so I just let it go.
오랫동안 이런 건 잘 못했어
I've been sort of bad
at this for a long time.
당신을 알기 전까지
Until you.
나도 사랑한다고 말하고 싶었어
I wanted to say I love you too.
쓰레기나 확인하러 가지
Let's go check the trash together.
비었어
Empty.
아세틸린? 프로판 가스?
Acetylene,propane?
아니, 암모니아야
No,ammonia.
뭐 하는 거야?
What are you doing?
뭐 하냐고?
난 FBI 요원이잖아
What are you doing? I'm a federal agent.
당장 화학물질 운반팀을 불러야겠어
We need to get a chem
transport team out here now.
내가 부르지
I'm on it.
핸드폰이 안 터져
No signal.
꼼짝 마!
FBI다!
freeze! Fbi!
총을 가지고 있다!
쏠 거야!
I have a gun! I will shoot!
존?
John?
뒤쪽에 도망가는 놈이 있어
생포해야 해
we got a runner in the
back. We need him alive.
바로 갈게
I'm on my way.
- 손 들어!
- 존!
- Hands in the air!
- John!
존
John.
오늘 운이 좋았어요. 던함 요원
you were very lucky today,agent dunham.
상처가 훨씬 심할 수도 있었어요
Your wounds could've easily
been much more severe.
스캇 요원은 운이 없었네요
Agent scott wasn't as fortunate.
폭발에서는 살아 남았는데
일종의 합성 화합물에 노출됐어요
While he survived the initial blast,agent scott
was exposed to some synthetic chemical compounds.
당신이 찾은 연구실에 있던 거죠
Work that was done
in the labs you found.
전염성은 없지만
좀 더 알아내기 전까지는
He's not contagious,but
until we understand more,
다른 사람에게 노출이
되지 않는 게 좋을 것 같아요
it's better not to introduce
any additional contaminants.
스캇 요원에게 영향을 주는
물질이 뭔지 아직 알 수 없어요
We haven't been able to identify
the substance that's affecting him.
CDC에서 전문가를 보냈지만...
The cdc has sent in specialists,but...
이런 건 처음 봤다고 하더군요
well,they've never seen anything
like what's happening here.
스캇 요원을 의도적 혼수상태로 만들었어요
We've put agent scott
in a drug-induced coma.
체온을 급격히 낮춰서
진행을 늦춰야만 했죠
His body temperature has been lowered
significantly to try and slow the progress.
유감이에요
I'm sorry,agent dunham.
감염
조직 손상
조직 경화
용해+피부
월터 비숍 박사
저예요
It's me.
연락 부서요
Liaison.
함부르크 비행기와 스캇 요원
사이의 관계를 찾아냈어요
I found a connection between the hamburg
flight and what's happened to agent scott.
월터 비숍이라는 사람이에요
His name's walter bishop.
케임브리지의 과학 연구원이죠
He's a scientific
researcher from cambridge.
1946년 생이고
하버드에서 공부했어요
Born in '46,harvard educated.
옥스퍼드와 M.I.T.에서 대학원을 다녔고요.
Post grad at oxford and M.I.T.
70년대에 하던 실험을 보세요
Look at the experiments
he was doing in the '70s.
비행기에서 일어난 일과 스캇 요원의
I believe dr. Bishop might have
information that might tell us
생명을 구하는데 뭔가
단서를 줄 수 있을 것 같아요
what happened aboard that plane
and save agent scott's life.
17년간 활동을 하지 않은 사람이잖아
Says the guy's been at
st. Claire's for 17 years.
저도 알아요
연구실에서 보조 연구원이 죽었죠
I saw that. An assistant
was killed in his lab.
소문에 의하면 인간을
실험체로 사용을 했대요
Rumors about dr. Bishop
using humans as guinea pigs.
살인죄로 고소 됐지만
정신 이상자로 간주 됐어요
He was charged with manslaughter,but
was deemed mentally unfit to stand trial.
왜 비숍이 가치가 있을 거로 확신하지?
Why are you so sure
bishop's worth our time?
왜 아니라고 확신하시는데요?
Why are you so sure he's not?
우리가 잘못 발을 들여 놓으면...
Listen,dunham,you and i
got off on the wrong foot--
이것과 제가 과거에 미국 해병대를
조사한 일이 당신을 화나게 한...
if my past job performance as U.S.
Marine special investigator offends you--
그래, 당연히 화가 나지
well,yeah,it does.
30년간 나라를 위해 봉사한 남자가
술을 약간 먹은 사소한 실수로
A man who serves his country for 30 years
has a few drinks and a small lapse in judgment
- 5년 형을 받았어
- 그 작은 실수로
- does not deserve five years.
- A small lapse in judgment that
3명의 어린 여자가 남은 인생을
괴롭게 살게 만들었어요
will haunt three young women
for the rest of their lives.
하지만, 그건 오늘 밤의 일과
관계가 없지 않나?
But that's not tonight's business,is it?
D.C.에서는 627편 비행기의 사고를
제대로 해결하라고 내게 임무를 줬어
Look,D.C.Has tasked me to make sure that our
reaction to flight 627 is beyond reproach.
여기 쓰인 바로는
1991년 영광스러운 매사추세츠 주에 의해
Now it says here,in 1991 the
glorious state of massachusetts
비숍 박사는 육친을 제외한
누구의 방문도 금지되어 있어
forbade dr. Bishop from having any visitors
with the exception of immediate family.
그러니 내가 보는 관점에서
자네가 정신 병원에 가서 애국심에 호소하고
So from where I sit,barging into a
mental institution waving the patriot act,
지금 자네에게 필요한 거지
which is what you'd need,
자네 생각에 내가 아는 한
and demanding face time
with some old lab rat
가장 끔찍한 테러의 배후라고 생각되는
나이 든 실험쥐와 면회를 하려면
who you think might be behind some of the most
terrifying terror that I can possibly imagine--
전 확실한 단서를 가져 왔는데
I'm coming to you with a solid lead,
- 당신은 개인적 원한으로 받아들이고...
- 자네는 내 시간을 낭비하고 있고
- And your personal resentment is preventing
you-- - and you're wasting your breath and my time.
"육친"이 무슨 뜻인지는 아나?
Do you understand "immediate family?"
비숍 박사에게 질문하고 싶으면
가장 가까운 친족을 데려와서
You want to question dr. Bishop,you go find
his next of kin and have 'em escort you in.
비숍 박사와 대화를 하고 숨겨진
실체를 알아오면 내가 뒤를 봐주지
Talk to bishop,uncover something
substantial,and I will have your back.
그때까지는 날 설득하려고 하지 마
Until then,I am not so convinced.
처리할 수 있나?
Now can you handle that?
아들이 있어요
He does have a son.
아들도 같은 지역에 사나?
Is his son local too?
그렇지는 않죠
Not exactly.
이라크 바그다드
BAGHADAD IRAQ
이자가 월터 비숍의 아들이군요
so this guy's walter bishop's son.
이름은 피터 비숍이에요
his name's peter bishop.
고등학교 중태에 IQ가 190인데
북미 천재 50위 안에 들죠
He's a high school dropout,I.Q.At
190,which is 50 points north of genius.
사회 부적응에 방랑자죠
Misfit,nomad.
2달 이상 한 직장에 있은 적이 없어요
Hasn't kept a job
longer than two months.
황무지 개간도 했고
소방관에 화물 조종사도 했었어요
He's been a wild land
fireman,cargo pilot,
잠시 대학의 화학과 교수도 했죠
and briefly a college
chemistry professor.
MIT 졸업장을 위조하고
He falsified a degree from M.I.T.
심지어 들키기 전까지
신문에 기고까지 했어요
And even managed to get a few papers
published before he was found out.
아주 골칫덩이로 들리네요
Sounds like a massive pain in the ass.
제 이력은 아주 구식이지만
my resume is hardly traditional.
이런 분야에서 구식은
더욱더 부적절하다는 뜻이죠
But around these parts,traditional
increasingly means irrelevant.
천억 불이 기반 시설에 들어가는데
당신들은 불을 켜기도 벅차요
$100 billion sunk into infrastructure
and you can barely keep the lights on.
그 말은 당신들에게 키르쿠크와 세이한
사이 600마일을 원유가 손상되지 않고
So you need someone to oversee construction
on 600 miles of pipeline to carry crude
통과하게 해줄 파이프 라인 건설을
관장할 사람이 필요한 거죠
between your fields in
kirkuk and the port of ceyhan.
추가로 전 녹지대 문제도 해결할 수 있죠
죽지 않고요
A job well outside the green zone,I
might add while I'm still alive to do so.
당신들은 유체역학 저항법률
문제도 해결할 사람이 필요해요
You'll need someone who has a handle
on the laws of hydrodynamic resistance.
혼합 오일의 열 교환이
문제가 될 수 있으니까요
The heat exchange in oil mixture flows.
또한 혼합정수계획법을
할 수 있는 사람이 필요해요
You'll also need someone who can
work with mixed integer programs
평탄하지 않은 지형을 지나는
파이프의 크기도 조절을 해야 하기 때문에요
because you're gonna have to resize the pipes
as you start working across uneven terrain.
물론 건설 비용을 줄이기를 원한다면요
That is,if you want to keep
down construction costs.
전 파르시어도 할 줄 알아요
I also speak farsi.
60만 불 괜찮네요
And 600,000 all in sounds fair.
피터 비숍 씨?
Peter bishop.
FBI의 올리비아 던함이라고 해요
Olivia dunham. I'm with the fbi.
네
Okay.
627편 비행기 들어 보셨나요?
You've heard of flight 627?
- 함부르크 비행기요. 들어 봤죠
- 그 문제로 도움을 부탁하려고요
The hamburg flight,of course.
You may be able to help us with that.
- 사람을 잘못 찾아온 것 같네요
- 월터 비숍 씨가 아버지 시죠?
No,I think you got the wrong guy.
Your father is walter bishop.
마지막으로 누군가 질문을
했을 때는 죄상 문제였는데요
You know,the last time somebody
asked me that it was an accusation.
대화를 해보려고 하는데
지금 박사님의 상태가
Well,he's the man we're looking to
speak with,but due to his current status,
당신만이 유일하게 허용이 돼서요
you're the only one who
can provide us access.
그 남자가 무슨 도움을 줄 수 있는데요?
And what possible help
could that man be to you?
그리고 내게 바라는 게 정확히 뭔데요?
And what is it exactly that
you're expecting me to do?
당신과 같이 매사추세츠로
같이 날아가자고요?
Hop on a plane with you
back to massachusetts?
난 이제 막 여기 왔어요/4일 내로
돌아오게 해 줄 수 있어요. 우선...
I just got here,honey.
I can have you on a return flight
here in four days,but first--
제가 시간 낭비를 줄여주죠
난 여기 이라크에 있는 게 좋아요
let me save you the time.
I'd rather stay here in iraq.
그만큼 보고 싶지 않다는 말이죠
That's how much I want to see my father.
인간으로서 부탁할게요
I'm going to beg you as
one human being to another.
당신 아버지가 어쩌면
죽어가는 사람을 살릴 수도 있어요
Your father may be able to
save someone who's dying.
제게 소중한 사람이죠
Someone I care about very much.
자기, 우린 모두
죽어가는 사람을 걱정해요
Sweetheart,we all care
about someone who's dying.
도울 수가 없네요
미안해요
I can't help you. I'm sorry.
당신이 왜 여기에 왔는지 알아요!
I know why you're here!
당신 기록을 가지고 있죠
I have your file.
무슨 기록이요?
What file?
FBI에서는 존재하지 않다고 말하는 기록이죠
The one the fbi would say doesn't exist.
거기에는 모든 것이 있어요
And it has everything.
당신이 어디에 있었고
무엇 때문에 도망을 다니고
Where you've been,what
you're running from.
여기서 당신이 뭐가 필요한지도요
And what you need while you're here.
그러니 나와 같이 가든지 특정 인물에게
당신이 어디 있는지 알리게 놔두던지 해요
So either you come with me,or I let
certain people know your whereabouts.
언제 떠나죠?
When do we leave?
의사가 다른 말은 하지 않았어?
did the doctors say anything else?
그래
Yeah.
고마워. 찰리
Thanks,charlie.
뭐 좀 물어보죠
Let me ask you something.
아버지랑 난 사이가 좋지 않아요
My father,not my favorite.
의심할 여지 없이 아버지는
자기 생각만 하고 뒤틀려 있고
He is without a doubt the
most self-absorbed,twisted,
독설가에 똑똑하지만 근시안적인
세계 최고의 나쁜 놈이죠
abusive,brilliant,myopic
son of a bitch on the planet.
화학자였어요
So he was a chemist.
그건 알고 있죠
That much I already know.
하버드의 지하 연구실에서
치약 회사를 위해 연구를 하는 것도 알죠
He worked out of a basement lab in harvard
doing research for a toothpaste company.
어느 날 연구실에서 사고가 있어
I also know that there was an
accident at the lab one night,
체포되는 바람에 우리 집이
처음으로 평화롭게 된 것도 알죠
that my father was arrested,beginning the
first truly peaceful period in our home.
문제는요
But here's the thing,olivia.
제 예감에 생명이 왔다 갔다 하는
당신 친구의 목숨을
My gut tells me that your friend's
life,the one hanging in the balance,
치약으로 구할 수는 없을 것 같네요
not gonna be saved by
a tube of toothpaste.
하버드에서 연구한 건 맞지만
치약 연구는 아니에요
He worked out of harvard,but
not on toothpaste.
캘빈 유전학이라고 하는
미군 비밀 실험을 하고 있었어요
He was part of a classified U.S.Army
experimental program called kelvin genetics.
원하는 모든 자원을 지원했어요
They gave him the resources
to do whatever work he wanted,
비주류 과학이라고 부르는 분야죠
which was primarily in an
area called fringe science.
비주류 과학이라면
사이비 과학을 말하는 거겠죠
When you say fringe
science,you mean pseudoscience.
아마도요
I suppose.
정신 조종, 염력, 심령체 투영
Things like mind
control,teleportation,astral projection,
투명인간, 유전 돌연변이
소생, 번식 같은 거요
invisibility,genetic
mutation,reanimation,fertility--
잠시만요
whoa,excuse for a sec.
소생이요?
정말요?
Reanimation? Really?
그러니까 당신 말은
So you're telling me what?
아버지가 프랑켄슈타인 박사란 말인가요?
My father was dr. Frankenstein?
매사추세츠 에식스 카운티
ESSEXCOUNTY MASSACHUSETTS
저기요
You know what?
당신만 가요
Why don't you go on ahead.
비숍 박사님, 특별한 날이네요
방문객이 있어요
Dr. Bishop,special
day. You have a visitor.
안녕하세요
Hello.
언젠가는 누군가 올지 알았죠
I knew someone would come... eventually.
비숍 박사님
Dr. Bishop.
비숍 박사님?
Dr. Bishop?
그러니까...
언제 일어난 일이라고 했죠?
And you said this was--
when did this happen?
비행기의 사고는 4일 전에 일어났어요
The incident on the plane
happened four days ago.
스캇 요원은 다음날 다쳤고요
Agent scott was injured the next day.
진피 피부가 이미 경화되고 투명화됐나요.?
The dermis already
indurated,translucent.
분자 조직이 보여요?
M-muscular tissue visible.
스캇의 피부 속을 볼 수 있느냐는 말인가요?
On scott,you mean,can
you see through skin?
그래요
Yes.
그건 좋지 않은데
Oh,that's not good.
피부 속을 볼 수 있다는 건...
미묘한 거죠. 진행이 됐다는 거예요
To see through the skin,it's--it's
tricky,it's advanced.
- 미묘해요
- 무슨 일이 일어나는 거죠?
- Like that it's tricky.
- What's happening to him?
되돌릴 수 있나요?
Can it be reversed?
뭐죠?
What is it?
여기는...푸딩 맛이...
They... they have this horrible...
끔찍해요
pudding here.
월요일에는 버터 스카치 푸딩을 주는데
정말 맛이 없죠
Butterscotch pudding on
mondays. It's dreadful.
오늘은 목요일이에요
It's thursday.
오, 그거 좋은 소식이네요
Oh,that's fantastic news.
되돌릴 수 있어요
It can be reversed.
당신 동료에게 일어난 일이요
What happened to your colleague.
몇 년 전 실험동물에 적용해 봤는데
Years ago I worked with
lab animals,and--and ...
일부는 괴로워했지만, 생명은 구했죠
some of them were
afflicted,but were saved.
뭘 해야 하는지 기억을 하나요?
So do you remember what to do?
그 장소, 치료법의 선택은...
This place,their- their
choice of therapies has c--c--
비숍 박사님
Dr. Bishop.
오늘 내 아들과 같이 왔군요
You came here today with my son.
친족을 제외하고
방문객을 받을 수 없으니까요
I'm not allowed visitors,you
see,except immediate family.
금지령이 바뀌지 않는 한
기껏해야 처방서 뿐이니
And unless the order has been
lifted,then it's a simple if/then formula.
당신이 여기 있다는 건
아들도 왔다는 뜻이죠
If you are here,then so is he.
정말...
I would... so much...
정말 아들이 보고 싶어요
so very much like to see him.
정말요
So much.
당신이 보고 싶으시데요
He asked for you.
자기, 고마워요
Thanks,sweetheart.
정말 감사해요
I really appreciate that.
당신이 여기 있다고 말하지 않았어요
Hey,I didn't tell him you were here.
그리고 다시는 "자기"라고 부르지 마요
And call me "sweetheart" one
more time. I'd really like that.
오랜만이네요
Hello,walter.
더 뚱뚱했던 걸로 기억하는데
I thought you'd be fatter.
더 뚱뚱했던 걸로 기억한다고요?
You thought I would be fatter.
처음 하는 말치고는 멋지네요
완벽해요
Excellent first words,perfect.
아니, 어렸을 때
넌 동글동글했어
No,as a boy,you were rounder.
네, 고등학교 여름 까지는요
Yes,I was until the
summer before high school.
그걸 기억할지는 몰랐지만요
Not that I'd expect
you to remember that.
잠시만 보자
May I see something?
뭐 하는 거예요?
손 치워요
What are you doing? Take
your hands off of me!
동공은 괜찮구나
잘 됐어. 정말 잘 됐어
Pupils are good. They're
good. Thank goodness.
당신 동료의 상태는 얼마나 진행됐나요?
How advanced is your
colleague's condition?
그게 내가...내가...
Which--which is
something I-I-I--
직접 진찰을 하지 않으면 알 수 없어요
I'm unable to deduce without
a firsthand examination.
직접 스캇을 봐야만 해요
I must see mr. Scott myself.
할 수 없지만요
Which I am unable to do.
현재 법으로는요
Well,under present law.
하지만...법률상 보호자가 있다면
친척 중에 말이죠
Unless--unless signed out by a legal
guardian who must be,once again,a relative.
지금 무슨 말을...
What are you
asking me to--
안돼요. 보호자요?
관둬요
no.Guardian? No,forget it.
- 할 거예요
- 아뇨, 하지 않아요
- He'll do it.
- No,I will not.
전화 한 통화만 하면 돼요
전화를 할까요?
One phone call. That's all it
takes. You want me to make it?
지금 주머니에 전화가 있거든요
'Cause I got my phone in my pocket.
지금은 주머니 밖에 있네요
Now it's out of my pocket.
내 아버지를 원했죠?
You wanted my father.
이제 아버지를 만났어요
Now you've got my father.
이제는 조심해야 할 거요
Which falls into the category of
be careful what you wish for...
자기
sweetheart.
627편 비행기에 무슨 일이 있었는지
알아내려는 많은 노력에도 불구하고...
every effort is being made to
understand what happened on flight 627...
비숍 박사님, 궁금한 게 있는데요
dr. Bishop,I was curious.
박사님 연구에 같이
참여한 사람은 없었나요?
Did anyone else ever
have access to your work?
조수는 산산조각이 났죠
Well,the assistants had bits and pieces.
아마도 신이 알겠죠
And god,I suppose.
벨리만이 유일하게 아는 사람일 거예요
I supposed the only one that really
knew what I was doing was belly.
누구요?
Who?
벨리, 윌리엄 벨인데
나랑 연구실을 같이 썼죠
Belly,william bell. He
and I shared the lab.
윌리엄 벨이요?
William bell?
메시브 다이너믹의 설립자와
연구실을 같이 썼어요?
You shared your lab with the
founder of massive dynamics?
미안하다
메시브 다이너믹이 뭔지 모르겠구나
I'm sorry,I don't know what
that is,massive dynamics.
별거 아니에요
그냥 아주 조그만 회사죠
Oh,nothing really. Just
a tiny little company.
죽이네요
That's perfect.
한 명은 지구에서
가장 부자 중 한 사람이 되고
One guys becomes one of the
wealthiest men on the planet.
다른 한 명은 정신 병원에 갇히다니
The other guy becomes an
institutionalized psychopath.
왜요?
무슨 일이에요?
What? What happened?
오줌을 쌌네요
I just pissed myself.
- 멋져요
- 그냥 오줌이야
- Excellent.
- Just a squirt.
메시브 다이너믹
MASSIVE DYNAMICM
막 메시지를 들었어
존은 어때?
I just got your message. How's john?
더 나빠
Worse.
CDC에서는 함부르크 비행기의
사고 원인이 합성물 때문이라고 하는데
Cdc says the hamburg flight was
caused by a synthetic compound.
그건 수증기 화합물이 '비'라고
하는 것과 마찬가지야
Which is like saying rain
is caused by a wet compound.
몇 가지 검사를 했지만
아무것도 나오지 않았어
They've run some tests on john,but
haven't come back with anything.
비숍은?
What about bishop?
어느 쪽으로 봐도
미쳤고 짜증 나
Left to right,insane and irritating.
유일한 희망이기도 하고
And also my only hope.
부탁 좀 할게
Listen...
윌리엄 벨과 만나야겠어
I need to question william bell.
자리 좀 만들어 줘
Could you set that up for me?
윌리엄 벨?
William bell?
메시브 다이너믹의 윌리엄 벨?
Massive dynamics william bell.
비숍과 같은 연구실을 사용했대
He and bishop used to share a lab.
농담이겠지
You're kidding.
비숍 박사님?
Dr. Bishop?
진저 에일 있나요?
진저 에일이요
(ginger ale= 생강 맛 탄산음료)
Is there ginger ale? Any ginger ale?
마셔본 지가 오래 돼서 그립네요
I haven't had some in
a long time. I miss it.
판스워스 요원, 박사님에게
진저 에일 좀 가져다주실래요?
Can we please get some ginger ale
for the doctor,agent farnsworth.
그러죠
Sure.
워, 멈춰요
멈춰요!
Whoa,stop right now! Stop!
걱정이 안 되나요?
Does this not concern you?
놔 주세요
Let him go.
페트리 접시
(Petri dish= 세균 배양용 접시)
Petri dish.
어서
Quick,please.
좋아
Good.
- 바로 내 연구실로 가져가야 해요
- 당신 뭐요?
- I need to take this to my lab right away.
- Your what?
하버드에 있는 크레스지 건물 지하죠
Kresge building basement,harvard.
바로 가야 해요
견본을 구했으니
We should leave.
I have my sample.
박사님이 떠나고 연구소는 폐쇄됐어요
Your lab was shutdown after you left.
뭐라고요?
I'm sorry?
정신 차려요
연구실은 없어요
Wake up. It's gone.
안돼
No.
안돼, 안돼, 안돼
No,no,no.
안돼, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼
No,no,no,no,no,no.
아빠, 연구실은 없어요
Walter,there is no lab.
완벽한 연구였다고
안돼!
- It's a perfect
working-- - no!
망할! 망할!
Damn you,damn you!
즉시 병원으로 보내야 해요
We need to get him back immediately.
연락 부서양
Liaison.
- 언제 돌아왔죠?
- 도움이 필요해요
- When did you get back?
- I need your help.
병원에서 월터 비숍 박사를
데려 나오는 데 성공했어요
I want you to know I've successfully had
dr. Walter bishop released from st.Claire's,
예전 연구실을 사용해야 하고요
and he requires the use
of his old laboratory.
뭐라고?
I'm sorry,what?
크레스지 건물이요
하버드 지하죠
Kresge building. Harvard,basement.
지난 17년간 대학에서
창고로 사용 중이에요
The university's been using it
for storage for the past 17 years.
이 사건에 대한 당신의 끈기가
It would be nice to think
that your tenacity in this case
뛰어난 부차적 결과와 강한 프로 정신에서
나온 것이면 좋겠군
is a byproduct of a remarkable
and robust professionalism.
하지만, 의문이 떠나지를 않는데
But I can't help but wonder
자네와 스캇 요원과의 관계에
뭔가 있는 게 아닌가 하고 말이야
if there wasn't something going
on between you and agent scott.
비숍의 연구실을 마련해 줘요
Get the lab for bishop.
정말
So much.
정말 많은 일이 여기서 있었죠
So much happened here.
앞으로도 있을 거고요
And so much is about to.
하버드 대학
HARVARD UNIVERSITY
과학 수사 기본 작업용품을 주문했어요
Dr. Bishop,I've ordered a
standard forensics work package.
더 필요한 건 없나요?
Is there anything else you need?
생체 조직 연구를 위한
광학 간섭 단층 촬영기와
Um,optical coherence
tomograph for flesh study.
900kg의 실리콘
2,000 pounds of silicon.
최소한 지원자 5명의 혈액 견본과
At least five anonymous blood
samples from volunteer donors.
미생물 탐지기
Microorganism detector.
NASA 등급으로요
아직 NASA는 있겠죠?
Nasa grade,of course.
There's still nasa,yes?
네
Yes.
오, 아직 있었구나!
Oh,she's still here!
이 탱크가 최고죠
Oh,this tank was the best.
2살짜리 유럽 가축 우도 필요해요
And a two-year-old
bos taurus.
뭐요?
A what?
소예요
A cow.
소를 가져 오래요
He wants a cow.
순종이 필요해요
혼혈은 안 돼요. 중요해요
Purebred,not crossbred.
This is important.
잘 발육된 390kg짜리로요
Mature weight,850 pounds.
체내 지방은 평균 2.37이어야 해요
Internal fat average of 2.37
농담하는 건가요?
Is he joking?
유전적으로 인간과 소는
몇 가닥의 DNA만 다르죠
Genetically,humans and cows are
separated by only a couple lines of dna.
윤리적 실험체로 필요한 거예요
So it's an ethical test subject.
그런 건 어디서 배웠죠? MIT인가요?
Where'd you learn that? M.I.T?
아뇨, 사실은
No,actually.
책에서 읽었어요
I picked that up reading books.
당신도 읽어보지 그래요
재미있어요
You should try it sometime. It's fun.
소를 가져와
Get him the cow.
멋져요
고마워요
Fantastic,thank you.
소보다 좋은 건 인간이지만
The only thing better
than a cow is a human.
우유가 필요하면 소가 필요하죠
Unless you need milk.
Then you really need a cow.
커피 드실래요?
Coffee?
고마워요
Thanks.
말해 봐요
Tell me.
제 기록에 또 뭐가 있죠?
얼마나 나쁜가요?
What else did that file say
about yours truly? How bad was it?
그 문제를 말할 자유가 없어요
I'm not at liberty to discuss it.
그냥 말하고 자유를 느끼는 건 어때요?
내가 여기 있잖아요
Why don't you go ahead and liberate
yourself,'cause I'm here now,
난 진실을 알 권리가
있다고 생각하지 않나요?
so I kind of feel like I
deserve the truth,don't you?
기록 같은 건 없군요
There was no file.
당신을 데려와야만 했어요
I needed you back here.
그게 무슨 뜻이죠?
허풍을 부렸다는 말인가요?
So that was what? You were bluffing?
전 절박했어요
I-I was desperate.
난 보통 사람의 마음을 잘 읽는데 말이에요
You know,I'm usually pretty
good at reading people.
그게 내가 하는 일이거든요
That's sort of what I do.
당신에게 문제가 있는 건 바로 알겠던데요
누구나 알 수 있을 정도였어요
Yeah,well,I could see you were
in trouble. Anyone could see that.
난 올 필요가 없었군요
So I could've stayed.
이라크에 있어도 됐었어요
I could've stayed in iraq.
오늘 아침 키르쿠크에서
자동차 폭발이 있었어요
You know,a car bomb went
off this morning in kirkuk.
내게 감사해야 하는 걸지도 모른다고요
You might just owe me a thank you.
뭐 여러 군데에 빚을 졌죠
Yeah,well,I owe a lot.
알겠네요
마피아 문제군요?
Tsk,yeah,I figured. MafiA.
빅 에디란 이름의 남자죠
A guy named big eddie.
빅 에디란 별명의 남자에게 빚을 졌어요?
You owe money to a guy
nicknamed big eddie?
빅 에디가 진짜 이름이에요
No,I owe money to a guy named big eddie.
법적으로도 바꿨다더군요
He had it legally changed.
그리고 난 도박꾼도 아니에요
그래 본 적도 없죠
And the thing is,I'm not even
a gambler. I mean,I never was.
단지...몇 년 전에 전 좀 미쳤었어요
It just-- a couple years
ago I went a bit crazy.
당신은 천재인지 알았는데요
체계가 있었을 거 아니에요
I thought you were a genius.
You must've had a system.
물론 체계가 있었죠
Of course there was a system.
도박장이 사기를 쳤었죠
The house was cheating.
하지만, 그 사실을 말하려고 하면...
But you try telling 'em that.
1972년 베트남에서
'72 during vietnam.
국방부 생화학 부서에서
베트공에 대적할 수단으로
The D.O.D.'S biochem division had
us working on a leprotic contagion
나병 전염병을 연구했었죠
for possible use against the vietcong.
비행기에 어떤 감염체인지는 몰라도
그 연구에서 나온 걸지도 몰라요
It's possible that whatever affected that
plane may have been derived from that work.
존은요?
What about john?
그에게 감염된 건 화학 작용으로
초기 실험 성분이지
What's infecting him is merely a chemical
reaction to the raw laboratory ingredients,
완성된 감염체가 아니에요
not the finished contagion.
그러니 반작용제를 합성할 수 있죠
Which means we can
synthesize a counteragent.
- 그럼 도울 수 있군요?
- 그러지 마요
- So you can help him.
- don't do that.
허황된 희망을 주지 마요
Don't give her false hope.
거짓이 아니야
진짜지
There's no false. It's
not false. It's real.
내가 도울 수 있어
I could help, yes.
폭발 때 그 창고에 있던
정확한 물질이 있다면
If I had a precise inventory of what was
in that storage facility when it detonated.
없어요
We don't have it.
모두 날아가 버렸어요
It all went up, everything.
답을 알지도 모르는 용의자는 도망가고
And the suspect who might
have those answers got away,
얼굴을 본 사람은 존 뿐이에요
and john was the only
one who saw his face.
얼마나 시간이 남았죠?
So how long does he have left?
현재 결정화 비율과
세포의 퇴화에 의하면...
Current rate of crystallization,
cellular degradation--
- 얼마나 남았어요?
- 24시간이요
- how long?
- 24 hours.
24시간이 지나면 뇌의
산소 공급이 끊길 거예요
His brain will no longer
be able to oxygenate itself.
정말 미안해요
I'm so sorry...
덜 위험한 해결법을 주지 못해서요
that I can't offer you a
less dangerous solution.
무슨 뜻이죠?
What do you mean?
제가 말을 하지 않았나요?
Didn't I mention it?
뭘 말했다고 생각하시는지는 몰라도
말하지 않았어요
Whatever you think you
said, you didn't say.
신경 전송 시스템이요
The synaptic transfer system.
꿈을 공유하는 거죠
The shared dream state.
꿈을 공유한다는 게 무슨 뜻이죠?
What do you mean shared dream state?
인간의 뇌는 다량의 전자기장을 생성해요
The human brain generates a
quantifiable electric field.
1976년에 2개의 다른 정신을
I posited in 1976 that it is possible
동조시켜 무의식 상태에서
to synchronize the fields
of two distinct minds
정보를 공유할 수 있게 하는 데 성공했죠
to allow the sharing of information
across the unconscious state.
2개의 깡통 사이의 실처럼요
Like a string between two tin cans.
정말 대단한 게 뭔지 알아요?
You know what's great about that?
그건 완전히 미친 짓이라는 거죠
Is that it's completely insane.
지금 혼수상태의 존과 대화를 해
You're saying I can
talk to john in a coma
용의자가 어떻게 생겼는지
들을 수 있다는 건가요?
and he can tell me what
the suspect looks like.
- 이건 정확히 과학이 아니에요
- 과학도 아니죠
- It's not an exact science.
- It's not even science.
전에 해본 적이 있나요?
Have you done this before?
이 기술을 이용해 시체에서
정보를 빼낸 적도 있어요
I have used this technique to extract
information from a corpse once.
죽은 지 6시간 이내에는 가능하죠
You can do that if they haven't
been dead for longer than six hours.
그렇죠. 왜냐면 6시간이 지나면
정말로 죽은 거니까
Right, 'cause after six hours,
that's when they're really dead.
당신이 그의 기억을 볼 수 있어요
You could access his memories.
뇌에 손상이 없다는 전제하에요
Assuming there's no brain damage.
물론 당신이 옷을 벗고 탱크 안에 들어가
Of course you'd have to
have an electromagnetic probe
몸을 담그는 동안에 당신 두개골에
전자기장 탐침을 설치해야 하지만요
placed in the base of your skull whilst
immersed without clothing in the old tank.
그리고 강한 약을 섭취해야 해요
And you'd be heavily drugged.
어떤 약이요?
What sort of drugs?
케타민, 뉴론틴, 환각제를 섞은 거죠
Oh, a mix of ketamine, neurontin,
lysergic acid diethylamide.
마지막 LSD는 산이에요
That last one is
lsd, by the way--acid.
몇 시간은 걸리니
Take at least a few hours.
문제가 없다면 이걸 합성하는데
네 도움이 필요하구나
I'd need your help to synthesize
it if it's not too much trouble.
네, 물론이죠. 문제 없어요
참도 재미있게 들리네요
Yeah, sure, no problem.
That sounds like fun.
저 사람은 정신 병원에서
이제 막 나온 사람이에요
The man who was just released
from the mental institution,
당신에게 과다 투약을 할 거고
he wants to give you a drug overdose,
당신 머리에 쇠막대기를 꼽고
옷을 벗겨 녹슨 탱크 물에 넣을 거예요
then sick a metal rod into your head and
put you naked into a rusty tank of water.
나도 그러고 싶지 않아
No, I don't want to.
안 하는 게 더 좋지
단지 할 수 있다고 말하는 것뿐이야
No, I'd rather not.
I'm just saying I can.
올리비아, 잠시만 기다려 봐요
Okay, olivia, excuse me for sec.
물론 당신은 정신적으로 힘들고
Now you're obviously
under severe duress,
이라크 이후로 잠도 못 자고
중요한 안자가 죽을지도 모르는 상황이지만
and you haven't slept since iraq,
and the man you care about might die,
분명히 말하는데
저 사람이 당신을 죽일 거예요
but I'm telling you
that man will kill you.
넌 이게 어떤 건지 모르잖아
You don't understand the procedure.
존이라면 날 위해 할 거예요
John would do it for me.
준비해 줘요
Set it up.
저는 국토안전부에 존을 이리
데려와도 좋다는 허락을 받으러 가죠
I'll get dhs authorization
to bring john here.
믿을 수가 없군요. 이건 미친 짓이에요
아빠는 미쳤어요!
This is unbelievable. This
is insane! He is insane!
당신도 미쳤고요
And you're insane for following him.
아주 좋아
Excellent.
환각제를 만들자고
Let's make some lsd.
이쪽에 둬요
put him over here.
소금 때문에 몸이 뜰 거예요
Salt'll make you float.
찰리, 윌리엄 벨과의 만남은 어떻게 됐어?
Charlie, did you get me
in to see william bell?
메시브 다이너믹은 기꺼이 도와주거나
예의가 있는 회사가 아니야
Massive dynamics isn't exactly
being forthcoming or courteous.
윌리엄 벨은 다음 주부터 2주간
미국 밖으로 나가 있을 거라더군
And apparently, william bell is out
of the country for the next two weeks.
이건 뭐야?
What's this?
저들의 일반적 권고가 적힌 메모지
A sweet little memo from
their general counsel.
그러니까 벨은 대화하기 싫다는 거야?
So bell doesn't want to talk?
그냥 500억 불 회사의
사장이라서 그런 걸지도
Or he's just being the head
of a $50 billion corporation.
웃기지 말라고 해
Oh, screw this.
윌리엄 벨의 사무실로 탱크를
몰고 가서 아는 걸 알아내고 싶네
I want to drive a tank through william
bell's office and find out what he knows.
나도 아는데 내가 온 이유는
나쁜 소식 때문이야
I know you do, but I'm here
to tell you the bad news.
법원의 명령을 받는데 48시간이 필요해
It's gonna be another 48 hours
till we get a court order.
이제 속옷을 벗어요
You should probably
strip to your underwear.
안녕 하쇼
Hello.
저건 무슨 뜻이야?
What the hell was that?
찰리, 우리에게 48시간이 없어
Charlie, we don't have 48 hours.
벨과 대화를 해야만 해
I need you to get to bell.
월터가 실패하면 벨이 유일한 희망이야
If walter fails, bell could
be the only one to save us.
리비, 무슨 일이야?
Livvy, what's happening here?
이거 전부 브로일스도 아는 거야?
You've cleared all this with broyles?
약간은
Somewhat.
약간이란 말이 거슬리는데
Somewhat doesn't sound good.
저거 소야?
Is that a cow?
응, 저건 유전자지
Yeah, that's gene.
찰리, 모든 수단을 쓴다고 약속해줘
Listen, charlie, I-I need you to
promise me you'll do whatever you can.
물론이지
너도 알잖아
Of course. You know that.
조심해
Be careful.
맙소사
My god.
내가 어디까지 했더라?
now where was I?
머리를 앞쪽으로 숙여요
Could you tilt your
head forward, please.
난 아직도 이 짓은
믿을 수 없다고 생각해요
I still think that this is deeply
irresponsible, and believe me, I would know.
이건 마취제예요
This is an anesthetic.
일반적인 양이면 될 거요
I feel normal working.
참도 그렇겠네요
Yeah, 'cause bootlegging smack in the
basement is just the picture of normalcy.
괜찮아요
제가 잡았어요
I got you. I got you.
당신 남자가 가치가 있는 사람이길 바라요
I hope your guy is worth it.
이건...
And this...
당신 의식을 활짝 열어 줄 거요
will rip open your consciousness.
다시 못 보게 될 경우를 대비해...
Listen, in case, you
don't come back, I just...
시작을 하기 전에 당신이 내게 해준
모든 점이 고마웠다고 말하고 싶네요
wanted to say before we do this, how
much I appreciate what you've done.
이런 곳에서는 많은 것을 잃죠
There are so many things you'll
lose in a place like that.
신뢰도 잃어 버리고요
You lose being trusted.
잃고 나서야 중요하다는 걸 아니 이상하죠
Strange how important
that is once it's gone.
보고 싶으면 더 가까이 와요
If you want to watch,
you can come closer.
여기서 일하나요?
Do you work here?
네, 전 아스트리드 판스워드예요
던함 요원의 조수죠
Yeah, I'm astrid farnsworth,
assistant to agent dunham.
누구요?
Who?
오, 그렇죠
난 월터...
Oh, yes. I'm walter...
비숍이에요
월터 비숍이요
bishop, walter bishop.
고마워요
Yes, thank you.
신경 쓰지 마세요
Don't mention it.
이게 던함의 뇌파죠
These are her brain rhythms.
대뇌 국부 상호작용으로 대부분의
사람이 아는 것보다 더 중요하죠
More important than most people know
regarding cerebral regional interaction.
아주 중요하죠
Critical.
그리고...이건 남자의 것이에요
And--and
these are his.
약이 효과를 거두는 사이 탐침에 의해
양쪽의 전기적 신호가 동기화될 거예요
As the drugs take effect, the probes will
synchronize the electrical signals from both.
뇌가 바로 그런 거죠
전기적 중계기요
That's what the brain
is, an electrical router.
다른 쪽에서 해석할 수 있는 거죠
Should be able to be
interpreted by the other.
정말 간단하네요
태피를 만드는 것처럼요
(taffy= 설탕, 버터, 땅콩으로 만든 사탕)
Yeah, simple really. Like making taffy.
뇌파가 동기화되면 같은 곳에
존재하는 거죠. 바로 지금이요
Then when the rhythms are in synch, they
should be in the same place, so to speak.
이제 뭘 하면 되죠?
So what do we do now?
이제 기다려야지
Now we wait.
뭐였죠?
What was that?
여보세요
여보세요!
Hello. Hello!
도착한 것 같아요
도착한 것 같아요. 왔어요
I think I'm here. I
think I'm here. I'm here.
존?
John?
저건 삼촌의 카누잖아
That's my uncle's kayak.
존? 당신이야?
John? Is that you?
- 올리비아
- 존
- olivia.
- John.
- 무슨 일이죠?
- 괜찮아
- What's happening?
- She's fine.
- 괜찮아요?
- 괜찮아
- She's all right?
- She's fine.
- 확실해요?
- 봐라
- You sure?
- Look.
당신을 생각 중이었어
I was just thinking about you.
저건 뭐죠?
What was that?
아무것도 아니야
Oh, nothing.
존...당신은 다쳤어
John... you were hurt.
기억이 나지 않아
I don't remember.
생각해 봐
Think.
창고
The storage units.
추위가 느껴져
I feel cold.
당신이 기억을 해줘야 해
I need you to remember.
뭘 기억해?
Remember what?
당신이 본 것
What you saw.
그자의 얼굴을 내게 보여줘
I need you to show me his face.
왜?
Why?
당신을 구할 수 있게
So I can save you.
제발 시도해 봐
Please try.
기억해 봐
Try and remember.
그래, 이거야
이거야
Yes, this is right. This is right.
뒤쪽에 도망가는 놈이 있어
생포해야 해
we got a runner in the
back. We need him alive.
얼굴을 볼 수가 없어
I can't see his face.
다리!
Her leg!
오, 그자를 봤어요!
Oh, I saw him!
존이 다치는 걸 봤어요. 난 거기 있었어요
난 거기 있었어요. 내가 봤어요
I saw john get hurt. I was there.
I was there, I saw--I saw him.
봤다는 게 무슨 뜻이야?
어디서?
What do you mean you saw him? Where?
물어보지 말라고 했잖아
I told you not to ask me that.
이자야. 이자가 우리가 찾는 용의자야
이렇게 생겼어
This is him. This is the suspect
we're looking for.He looks like this
이미지를 보내 줘요
기록과 비교할게요
send me the image. I'll
put it through the database.
잠은 잤어?
엉망으로 보여
Have you slept? You look like crap.
전과자와는 맞는 부분이 없어요
No primary matches for criminal record.
모든 주의 운전 면허증과 비교하고
지역 내 모든 병원에 이미지를 보내요
Well, cross-check all state driver license
files and send this image to all local hospitals.
던함 요원, 이걸 좀 봐요
Agent dunham, take a look at this.
맙소사. 이자야
Oh, my god. This is him.
627편의 승객이었어요
He was a passenger on flight 627.
- 이해를...이해를 할 수가 없어
- 잠깐, 잠깐
- I don't-- I don't
understand. - Wait, wait, wait.
창고에 있었을 수가 없잖아
He couldn't have been
at the storage place.
- 찰리, 내가 봤어
- 잠깐만요
- Charlie, I saw him there.
- hold on, guys.
모건 스티그는 108번 승객이었죠
Morgan steig was passenger number 108.
비상 연락책은 리차드 스티그예요
His emergency contact, richard steig.
쌍둥이란 말인가요?
You're telling me he has a twin?
네, 집 주소는 없고
고용 기록만 있네요
Yeah, no home address, only
a history of employment.
왜?
What?
리차드 스티그의 마지막 고용주
Richard steig's last employer.
뉴욕의 메시브 다이너믹
윌리엄 벨과 대화 좀 하고 싶은데요
I was hoping to speak with william bell.
MASSIVE DYNAMIC NEW YORK
전 니나 샤프예요
전무이사죠
I'm nina sharp, executive director.
몇 분 밖에 시간이 없네요
I only have a few minutes.
유력 용의자가 여기서 일을 했어요
리차드 스티그라고 하죠
our primary suspect is a former
employee of yours, richard steig,
그자가 당신 회사의 연구실에서 개발한
자가 박멸 독소를 사용했을지도 몰라요
who may have used research from your company
to develop a self-eradicating airborne toxin.
이유나 누구를 위해 그런지는 모르지만
자신의 동생마저 희생할 의지가 있는 사람이죠
We don't know why or for whom, but it appears
he was willing to sacrifice his own brother.
무엇이 승객을 죽였는지는 모르지만
그자의 인슐린 펜에 들어 있었어요
Whatever killed those people on that
plane got onboard through his insulin pen.
이제 말할 게 있나요?
So do you want to talk to me?
데니엘
Danielle...
리차드 스티그에 관한 모든 걸 모아서
여기 던함 요원에게 줘요
please assemble everything we have on
richard steig for agent dunham here.
리차드 스티그를 기억해요
I remember richard steig.
저희 무기 시스템 연구실에서 일했죠
He worked in our weapons
systems research lab.
3달 전에 기밀 기술 정보를 빼내려고 했었죠
He was caught three months ago trying to
leave the premises with classified information.
즉시 해고를 했고
He was terminated immediately.
법무부에 이름을 알렸어요
We referred his name to
the justice department.
해야 할 일을 했죠
We have done our due
diligence, agent dunham.
이 문제로 우리 회사나
벨 박사의 이름이 유출되면
And if you choose to drag our company
and dr. Bell's name into this matter,
저희 변호사에게 연락을 받을 거예요
you will be hearing from our attorneys.
벨 박사님 밑에서 얼마나 일을 했죠?
How long have you worked for dr. Bell?
16년이요
16 years.
난 내 인생을 메시브 다이너믹에 바쳤고
이건 과장이 아니에요
I owe massive dynamics my life,
and that is not an exaggeratioN.
전 육상 선수였죠
I s a runner most of my life.
97년도 보스톤 마라톤에서
이상하게 피로감을 느꼈어요
In the '97 boston marathon,
I felt strangely tired.
어느 날 벨 박사님이 제 불편함을 보고
단층 촬영을 권하더군요
One day at the office, dr. Bell noticed my
discomfort and insisted I go for a cat scan.
암이었죠
Cancer.
너무 많이 퍼져서
바로 팔을 절단해야만 했어요
Spread so severely I had to
have my arm amputated that week.
이 회사에서 만든 촬영기로
제 암을 찾아냈어요
That first scanner that found my
cancer was built by this company.
제 수술에 쓰인 보조 로봇 장비와
후에 복용한 약도
The robotic assist tools there were used in
my surgery, the drugs I took afterwards...
메시브 다이너믹에서
개발하고 만들어진 거죠
were developed and manufactured
by massive dynamics.
제 의수도 벨 박사님이 직접 만들었고요
And my replacement limb was
designed by bell himself.
리차드 스티그에 관한 전부예요
Everything we have on richard steig.
스티그도 패턴의 부분인가요?
Do you believe that steig
may be part of the pattern?
네? 부분이요?
I'm sorry, part of the...
패턴의 부분이요?
part of the pattern?
취급 허가가 있는 줄 알았네요
Oh, I assumed you had clearance.
당신에게 있는 취급 허가는
제게도 허가가 되어 있어요
Well, I'm cleared to know whatever
you're cleared to know, ms. Sharp.
아닌 것 같네요
Apparently not.
하지만, 이건 말해 주죠
과학과 기술이
But suffice to say that we've reached
a point where science and technology
기하급수적으로 발전하는 순간이 되면
have advanced at such an
exponential rate for so long,
우리 능력으로 규제하고
통제할 수 없을 수도 있다는 거요
it may be way beyond our ability
to regulate and control them.
당신이 어디에
발을 들였는지 아는 게 좋아요
You should know what you're
getting into, agent dunham.
내 딸이었다면 이렇게 말해 줄 거예요
I would say this to my own daughter.
조심하고
Be careful.
행운을 빈다고요
And good luck.
나무 벌레는 네가 가져. 샌디!
우린 집에 갈 거야!
Keep the tree warm, sandy!
We're on our way to your house!
이게 아이용이라고요?
And this is a show for children?
네, 인기 좋죠
Yeah, it's huge.
스펀지의 이야기를 놀랍게도 깊이 담았네요
Surprisingly profound for
a narrative about a sponge.
미친 사람 집입니다
Crazy house.
방금 로건 공항에 도착했어요
그쪽으로 가는 중이에요
I just landed at logan.
I'm on my way to you.
용의자의 위치를 알아낸 것 같아요
I think we've located our suspect.
잠깐만요
그 남자를 찾았어요?
Hold on a second. You found the guy?
꿈에서 본 남자를 찾았군요
You found the guy from your dream.
두 분 다 데리러 가는 중이에요
I'm picking you both up.
박사님이 그자에게 질문해서
I need your father
there to question him,
존을 구하는데 뭐가 필요하든
정보를 알아내야 해요
get whatever information he needs
so he can make the cure for john.
당신도 있어야 해요
혹시라도 박사님이...
And I need you there too
in case your father's--
거기까지만 말해요
거기서 보죠
say no more. We'll meet you out front.
남쪽을 주시하도록
stay eyes on south side.
레드 팀, 준비해
red, stand by.
지붕 위, 위치를 확인하도록
rooftop, confirm your position.
보스턴 남부
S*** BOSTON
한 명이 나온다
Got one coming out.
이쪽으로 가세요
This way, ma'am.
이상무! 이상무! 이상무!
Clear! Clear! Clear!
뒤쪽이야!
In the back!
네 혈압을 확인하고 싶은데
I'd like to... check
your blood pressure.
아빠 혈압이나 검사해요
난 괜찮아요
Why don't you check your own blood
pressure? Mine's fine, thanks.
네 피부의 색을 보니
동맥성 고혈압으로 고생하는 것 같은데
Your skin tone suggests you might be
suffering from arterial hypertension.
제가 뭐로 고생하던 상관 마세요
Don't tell me what I'm suffering from.
그리고 고혈압은 눈으로 확인할 수 없어요
And there are no visible
signs of hypertension.
문제가 해결된 후
제발 날 돌려보내지 말아줘
When this over, please
don't send me back.
돌아가고 싶지가 않구나
I don't want to go back.
아빠...
Look,
walter--
이 경험은...네가 날 꺼내 줬는데...
this experience...You
woke me up again, and...
다시 돌아갈 수가 없구나
you can't put me back to sleep.
제 생각이 아니었어요
전부요
It was hardly my idea, any of it.
네가 생각하는 내 형벌이 뭐든지
Whatever punishment you think I deserve,
맹세하는데 이미 많은 고통을 겪었어
I swear I have already endured it.
17년이야
제발...
17 years. Please...
아들아
son.
왜?
What?
골목에 있어요!
He's in the alley!
내가 차에서 내려도 되겠니?
Can I get out of the car?
그냥 있어요!
Stay right there, walter!
질문이 좀 있는데
We've got some questions for you.
미국법 1111
U.S.Code 1111.
147명의 승객 살인
The murder of 147 passengers.
미국법 2332-A
U.S.Code 2332-A.
대량 파괴 무기 사용
Use of weapons of mass destruction.
미국법 2332-B
U.S.Code 2332-B.
국경을 초월한 테러활동
An act of terrorism
transcending national borders.
국제법 1113
U.S.Code 1132-A.
정부요원 살인 미수
Attempted murder of a federal agent.
사면을 원해?
You want immunity.
저장 시설에 있던 모든 화학물질의
합성물을 자세하게 알아야겠어
I want a detailed account of all the synthetic
chemicals you had in that storage facility.
전부 적어
Write them down.
그럼 협정문에 대해 얘기하지
And then we can talk about an agreement.
말할...것이...없소
I... have nothing... to say.
아빠, 여기 있어요
Walter, stay here.
어디 가는...
Where
are you--
화합물이 스캇 요원에게 피해를 줬어
the compound affecting agent scott.
수용성 물질이지?
It's water soluble, right?
이게 뭔지는 모르지만
어떤 효과가 있는지는 알지!
We might not know what it
is, but we know what it does.
그러니 내가 원하면
시체에서 전염성 액체를 뽑아내
So if I wanted to, I could extract the
contagious fluids from his body and...
언제든 네 몸 안에 넣어줄 수 있지
that would allow me to slip
it to you whenever I wanted to.
네 음식이든
In your food.
커피든
A cup of coffee.
화장실이든 말이야
The toilet.
무슨 일인지 누구도 알지 못할 거야
Nobody would ever know how it happened.
유일한 문제는
The only problem is...
방금 여기 있던 여자의 친구가
죽어가고 있다는 거지
the woman who was just in here,
that's her friend who's dying.
그래서 그럴 시간이 없어
So I just don't have that kind of time.
안돼!
No!
화합물에 대해 말해!
Tell me the chemicals!
그만 해요!
이러면 안 돼요. 이러면 안 돼요
Hey, stop, stop! You
can't! You can't do that.
아뇨, 당신이 이러면 안 되죠
No, you can't do that.
화학 물질의 이름을 말해
I want the names of the chemicals.
하나를 세지
I'm gonna count to one.
하나!
One!
독소의 활동은 에틸렌 글리콜을
기반으로 한 마그네슘이야
The active toxin was a
magnesium based ethylene glycol.
안 돼요. 저도 이해는 하지만
제 말을 들어 봐요
No, I understand that, but
you're not listening to me.
마그네슘 에틸렌 글리콜과
유기인산 화합물을 결합하면...
Magnesium ethylene glycol
with an organophosphate trig--
아빠, 잠시만요
walter, just stop for a second.
스캇의 혈액이 흡수하기 전에
부작용으로 죽게 될 거예요
His blood won't be able to absorb
it before the side-effects kill him.
네 주장이 뭔데? 티아민을 기반으로 한
칼슘 글루콘산염을 합성하자고?
So you're saying what?
We synthesize a calcium
gluconate in a thiamine base?
네, 바로 그거예요
Yes, exactly.
안돼. 스캇의 혈액이 더 필요한데
전혀 없어
We can'T. We'd need more
of his blood. We have none.
그렇지 않아요
That's
not true--
모든 요원은 부상을 대비해
혈액이 준비되어 있어요
all agents are required to set up a
backup blood supply in case we're wounded.
- 자가수혈, 멋져
- 자가수혈, 멋져요
autologous transfusion.
That's brilliant.
해독제를 만들어 그냥 스캇의
저장된 피에 용해시키면 돼요
We can create the antidote and then just
dissolve it into scott's stored blood.
정맥에 수혈을 하면
거부반응이 없을 거예요
If we transfuse him intravenously,
his body won't be overwhelmed.
A+를 주마. 아주 잘했어
시작하자
A+, boY. Well done. Let's begin.
내게 연구실이 생긴 건가?
So I got the lab.
네, 그러게요
Yeah, I know you did.
고맙워요
Thanks.
아래층은 어찌 돼가지?
How's it goin' downstairs?
박사님 말로는 시간이 좀 걸리지만
길조가 보인다고 하더군요
bishop says it'll be awhile,
but that it's looking auspicious.
박사님의 말이에요
That was his word.
왜요?
What?
일을 아주 잘했어
You've done some solid work here.
비숍의 위치를 알아내
당신 일을 돕게 했지
Locating bishop. Getting him out.
Finding a way to get him to work with you.
우린 아주 감명을 받았어
We're impressed.
우리라는 게 누구죠?
Who's "we"?
비행기의 사건은 단순한 테러보다
훨씬 위험한 일의 부분일지도 몰라
What happened on that plane might be part of
something more dangerous than just simple terrorism.
단순한 테러요?
Simple terrorism?
지난 9개월간 함부르크의 비행기와
비슷한 사건이 30건이 넘어
In the past nine months, there have been three dozen
authenticated incidents like the hamburg flight.
존 톰슨, 1998년에 사라진 평범한 아이지
John thompson, normal kid,
went missing back in '98.
지난달에 지구 반대편에 나타났는데
나이를 전혀 먹지 않았어
Reappeared last month halfway
around the world. Hadn't aged a day.
지난 몇 달간 같은 해에 실종된
46명의 아이가 나타났어
In the past few months, 46 other children
who went missing that same year turn up.
같은 조건으로
Same story.
스리랑카 해변의 어부가 저공비행을 하는
비행기에서 고주파를 내뿜어
Local fisherman off the coast of sri lanka reports
a low-flying plane emitting a high-pitch frequency
모든 유리창을 깼다고 신고했지
that blows out all their windows.
한 시간 후 같은 곳에서
An hour later, same spot,
8.7 진도 지진이 일어나
해일로 8만 3천 명이 죽었어
an 8.7 sub-surface earthquake creates
a tsunami that kills 83,000 people.
- 왜 제게 이런 이야기를 하는 거죠?
- 이 남자는
- So why are you
telling me-- - this man.
리스본에 있던 환자인데 몇 년 만에
혼수상태에서 깨어나 숫자를 쓰기 시작했는데
A patient in lisbon who woke up after
years in a coma began writing just numbers.
태평양에 있는 우리 전투 선단의
정확한 실시간 좌표로 밝혀졌지
They turn out to be exact real-time coordinates
of our carrier battle groups in the pacific.
정보부에서는 최고 기밀로 분류시켰고
Intel that's classified
above top-secret.
그게 가능이나 한 일인가요?
So how is that even possible?
나랑 같이 일을 하지
그럼 허가를 내줄게
Come work for me, and I'll
get you the clearance--
그만 해요
oh, stop.
- 던함, 더 들어야 할 것이 있어
- 제 말을 듣지 못했나요? 그만 하라고 했어요
Dunham, there's more you need to hear.
You must not have heard me. I said stop.
이런 현상을 "패턴"이라고 부르지
They're calling these
events "the pattern."
누군가 실험을 하고 있어
전 세계가 그들의 연구실이지
As if someone out there is experimenting,
only the whole world is their lab.
이제 자네도 봤고 알잖아
You've seen it, now you know.
알고 싶지 않아요
난 직업이 있다고요
I don't wanna know. I have a job.
이건 더 중요한 직업이에요
This is a more important job.
당신이 필요한 건
뭐든지 누구든지 구해주지
Anything, anybody you
need, you can have.
내가 가진 이 직업이 좋아요
I like the job I've got.
당신이 깔보는 내 동료가 좋고요
And the man I do it with. Which you
seem to have deduced on your own.
주위를 둘러봐
Look around.
많은 사람이 살아가고 있지만
You see all these people
going about their lives.
주변에서 무슨 일이 일어나는지
어떤 상황에 놓였는지 전혀 몰라
No idea what's happening around
them, what they're in the middle of.
난 그냥 이전으로 돌아가고 싶어요
I just wanna go back to before.
던함, 이미 늦었어
Dunham. I don't think you can.
일어났어
깨어났어
He's up. He's awake.
올리비아, 올리비아!
깨어났어요. 의식이 돌아왔다고요
Olivia, olivia, he's
awake! He's conscious.
존?
John?
존, 내 말이 들려?
John, can you hear me, baby? Baby?
당신 꿈을 꿨어
I had a dream about you.
스캇 요원이 갈아입을 옷이에요
Uh, a change of clothes for agent scott.
생명력이 놀라울 만치 강해요
His vitals are surprisingly strong.
얼마나 오래 입원을 해야 하죠?
So, um, how long does he have to stay?
피부의 멜라노사이트가 재생성 돼야 하지만
일주일 이상 걸리지는 않을 거예요
Until the melanocytes in his skin have
regenerated, but that shouldn't be more than a week.
당신이 생명을 구했어요
He owes you his life.
서로 구했죠
We owe each other.
스티그는 어떤 방에 있죠?
What room is steig in?
아는 건 전부 말했잖아요
I told you everything I know. Didn't I?
합성하는데 들어간 모든
화합물의 이름을 알려줬어요
I gave you the names of all the
synthetics I used in the compound.
걱정 마요
사면 협정문은 아직 유효하니
Don't worry, our
immunity agreement holds.
하지만, 더 얘기해야 할 것들이 많아요
But there's still a whole lot
more we have to talk about.
예로 자신의 동생을 죽인 이유 같은 거요
Like, why you killed your own brother?
당신이 만든 걸 누구에게 파는 지도요
And who you're selling your work to?
내가 팔았다고 누가 그러던가요?
Who says I was selling it?
당신 사무실의 남자가 날 협박했어요
I was threatened by a
guy from your office.
내가 거짓말을 하는 것 같나요?
You think I'm lying?
신에게 맹세하죠
I swear to god.
증명할 수도 있어요
대화도 녹음했어요
I can prove it.
- 녹음한 건 어디 있죠?
- 숨겨뒀죠
- Where's the recording?
- I buried it.
이게 누구야?
Who is this?
교환 조건이 있었잖아
we had an exchange agreement.
다른 입찰자가 있었어
hmm, there have been other bidders.
오늘 비행기는 실험에 불과해
Today, the airplane was a demonstration.
넌 쓸데없이 주의를 끌었어
you've drawn unwarranted attention.
우리가 거래하기 어려워졌다고
Something we can't afford
to be connected with.
간단하게 말하지
다른 누구에게도 팔지 마
I'll make this simple. You're
not selling to anyone else.
만약 팔면 우리가 널 쫓을 거야
You do that, we will come after you.
내가 직접 잡아주지
I will come after you.
내가 친동생에게 하는 짓을
보고도 날 위협하는 건가?
you're threatening me after seeing what
I'm willing to do to my own brother?
확실히 해주지
우린 널 기꺼이 가족처럼 대해줄 수 있어
well, let me assure you, we'd be
happy to treat you as family too.
확실히 해주지
우린 널 기꺼이 가족처럼 대해줄 수 있어
Well, let me assure you. We'd be
happy to treat you as family too.
스캇 특수요원이요
Special agent scott.
네, 들어가시죠
Yes, sir, go right ahead.
찰리, 요원 2명을 스캇 요원 방에 배치해
charlie, I need two agents posted
outside agent scott's room now.
스티그도 살펴보고
Check on steig.
바로 하지
I'm on it.
5분 거리야
I'm five minutes away.
이곳을 봉쇄해!
We need this place locked down!
여기는 던함, 요원 ID는 52776 팬웨이
남쪽으로 파란색 사륜차를 쫓고 있습니다
This is dunham, agent I.D.52776 In pursuit
of blue suv heading south on fenway.
즉시 지원팀을 보내주세요
Need immediate assist.
자신에게 물어 봐
왜...
Ask yourself why...
왜 브로일스가 널 저장 시설로 보냈는지
why broyles sent you
to the storage facility.
왜 너인지
Why you?
왜? 이해를 못 하겠어
Why? I don't understand.
누구를 위해서 일한 거야?
Who are you working for?
존, 말해줘
John, tell me.
더 말해줘
Tell me more, john.
나도 너만큼 오래 알았어
I knew him just as long as you did.
유감이야
I'm sorry.
일이 10년 전과 달라
Job isn't what it was ten years ago.
우린 세상을 보호해야 하잖아
We're supposed to protect a world
근데 조금만 실수를 해도 죽어버리니
where one breath of the wrong air can
incinerate you from the inside out.
내 말은 어떻게 사람을 보호해
I mean, how do we protect people
회사가 우리보다 높은
보안 허가 권한이 있는데
when corporations have higher
security clearances than we do?
우리가 조사한 일의
반도 보고를 받지 못하잖아
When we're not fully briefed on half
the things that we're investigating?
진실은...
You know, when the truth...
진실은 우린 쓸모없는 존재라는 거야
the truth is we're obsolete.
연구실로 데려다 줘
Take me back to the lab.
잠시 얘기 좀 해요
Can I talk to you please?
네
금방 올게요
Yeah. I'll be back in a second.
가능한 한 이곳에서
멀리 떠나고 싶은 거 알아요
Though I'm sure you're anxious to
get as far away from here as possible.
이라크나 아프가니스탄이나
무수히 많은 다른 곳으로요
To iraq or afghanistan or
countless other out of reach places,
하지만, 제가 여기 온 건, 당신 아버지는
남아야 한다고 말하기 위해서 예요
but I'm here to tell you that
your father needs to stay.
그 말은 당신도 남아야 한다는 거죠
Which means that you need to too.
괜찮아요?
Are you okay?
당신이 이곳에 남기 싫어하는
이유가 무수히 많다는 건 알지만
No, I-I-I-I know that you have countless
reasons as to why this is a non-starter for you.
하지만, 내 말은...
당신 아버지는 좋은 사람이에요
But, I mean, your father is a good man.
당신 생각처럼 괴물이 아니에요
He's not the monster you think he is.
당신 생각과는 달리
둘이 잘 지내고 있어요
And you're good with him,
despite what you think.
박사님과 대화가 통하는
사람도 당신뿐이고요
And you're the only
one who speaks walter.
병원으로 다시 데려가면 전부 끝이에요
We take him back to st.
Claire's and it's all over.
존은 어디 있죠?
Where's john?
기관에 얘기해서
당신 도박빚은 처리해 줄게요
I can talk to the agency and get
them to clear your gambling debts.
내 빚은 내가 처리할 수 있어요
무슨 일이에요? 존은 어디 있죠?
I can take care of my own debts,
okay? What just happened? Where's john?
더는 가짜 위협은 하지 않을게요
I'm not gonna use false
threats with you anymore.
그럴 필요도 없죠
I don't need to.
위협은 실제로 있으니까요
The threats are real.
당신이 떠나고 아버지와 대화를 했는데
의식이 아주 맑았어요
After you left, my father sat down and started
talking to me and he was remarkably lucid.
아버지와 윌리엄 벨이
연구한 일에 대해서 대화를 했죠
He told me about the work. That he and
william bell had done their experiments.
비행기의 사고는 시작에 불과해요
And that incident-- what happened
on the plane is just the beginning.
그래서 어서 빨리 보스턴을 떠나고 싶어요
Which makes every part of me feel
like I gotta get the hell outta boston.
안 가니?
are we leaving?
안 가느냐고?
Are we leaving?
죽은 지 얼마나 됐죠?
How long has he been dead?
5시간이요
five hours.
질문을 해요
Question him.
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
sync:峠흄흄